A Guide to the University of Connecticut 1979.0014
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
University of Connecticut, Peoples of Connecticut Project Records
1897-1980
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
1979.0014
24 Linear Feet
The "Peoples of Connecticut" Project was begun in 1974 under a grant from the Ethnic Heritage program, Office of Education, Department of Health, Education and Welfare. The goal of this program was to increase awareness, within Connecticut secondary schools, of different ethnic groups. Using curriculum guides and other instructional materials, the project endeavored to provide teaching and learning tools for discovering the cultural diversity of Connecticut's residents.
History
The "Peoples of Connecticut" Project was begun in 1974 under a grant from the Ethnic Heritage Program, Office of Education, Department of Health, Education and Welfare (now Health and Human Services). The goal of this program was to increase awareness, within Connecticut secondary schools, of different ethnic groups. Using curriculum guides and other instructional materials, the project endeavored to provide teaching and learning tools for discovering the cultural diversity of Connecticut's residents.
The Project is divided into three distinct parts. Dr. Frank Stone, School of Education, is primarily responsible for the publication of the curriculum guides. Dr. Bruce Stave, History Department, is responsible for the oral histories, and Dr. William D'Antonio, Sociology Department, and Fred Grupp (Administrative Assistant for the project) have been in charge of collecting research materials and for some demographic mapping. By 1978, seven curriculum guides were published in pilot editions. These guides focuses on the Armenians, Irish, Italians, Jews, Puerto Ricans, Poles and Scots/Scots- Irish.
Responsibility for the papers that are now collectively labeled "The Peoples of Connecticut Project" comes from several sources. Because the project was actually split into three distinct parts, the papers themselves came from different places before they were combined to form this collection. Dr. Frank Stone was responsible for the publishing of the curriculum guides and his files. Dr. Bruce Stave was responsible for the oral histories, which are now available through the Center for Oral History Catalog of Interviews (available online). The remaining materials were collected by Dr. William D'Antonio and Mr. Fred Grupp.
Scope and Content
The collection contains a wide variety of materials more specifically detailed in the series descriptions. All aspects of the project are documented in the collection from the working papers of the grant to the published curriculum guides and bibliographies. Reference and resource materials pertinent to the ethnic groups represented by Connecticut's residents are included in Series IV-VII. The collection also includes some general reference materials pertaining to these ethnic groups in the United States, as well.
Series IX-XI include similar information to that found in Series I-III. The later series appears to be materials added at a later date and not integrated into the processed collection.
Organization
SERIES I: ADMINISTRATIVE RECORDS (undated, 1974-1979) contains the records of the administrative and financial aspects of the project. Included are progress reports and press releases, as well as personnel information and budget and grant proposals.
SERIES II: WILLIAM D'ANTONIO FILES (undated, 1946-1976) contain the papers and research materials of Professor William D'Antonio of the Sociology Department, one of the principle creators of the collection. Of significance within this series is a fairly large body of information pertaining to voluntary associations, as well as some ethnic and sociological newsletters and articles.
SERIES III: FRANK STOME FILES (undated, 1971-1980) are comprised of the papers of another creator of the collection, Professor Frank Stone of the School of Education. Works of Stone himself constitute a major part of this series, but also included are the works of students of Stone.
SERIES IV: CURRICULUM GUIDES (undated, 1975-1978) contains the pilot editions of the curriculum guides that were published between 1974 and 1978. Both the rough drafts and the published guides are included for each ethnic group.
SERIES V: RESEARCH MATERIALS OF BESSIE BLOOM WESSEL (1924-1944) are the papers of Mrs. B. B. Wessel, a woman who conducted extensive research on ethnicity in Connecticut, particularly the New London area, During the 1930s and 1940s. Also of interest in this series is a group of clippings from the New London Day (1933-1940), collected by Mrs. Wessel.
SERIES VI: RESARCH MATERIALS ON ETHNIC GROUPS (undated, 1897-1980) constitutes the major bulk of this collection. This series contains the research materials on each ethnic group within Connecticut. The material in this series is first arranged alphabetically by ethnic group (regardless of geographical location). Within each ethnic-group subseries the materials are then arranged by geographical location, from the most specific to the most general (i.e. first pertaining to city within Connecticut, then to the State of Connecticut, then regarding no specific location). Within each of these divisions, the organization is by the type of document. Included are biographies, oral histories, newspaper clippings, ethnic newspapers and newsletters as well as a small number of ethnic cookbooks.
SERIES VII: RESEARCH MATERIALS ON ETHNICITY AND IMMIGRATION (undated, 1936-1979) contains the research materials relating to the general topics of ethnicity and immigration with special emphasis on Connecticut. Again the type of material within this series is varied, including reference works (such as bibliographies and directories) and research papers, as well as information on other ethnic heritage programs within the United States.
SERIES VIII: RESEARCH MATERIALS ON LOCAL HISTORY (undated, 1930-1979) includes a small amount of information on localities outside of Connecticut. This series contains church and religious community histories for some of the localities.
SERIES IX: ADDENDUM: ADMINISTRATIVE RECORDS (undated) contains office files from the Ethnic Heritage project, and includes correspondence, grant project data, minutes of Project meetings, and information on similar projects at other institutions.
SERIES X: ADDENDUM: WILLIAM D'ANTONIO FILES (undated) contains papers relevant to the Ethnic Heritage Project, and includes bibliographies, a course prospective, and studies and thesis relevant to the subject of ethnicity.
SERIES XI: ADDENDUM: RESEARCH MATERIALS ON ETHNIC GROUPS (undated, 1974-1976) contains printed materials such as association guides, newsletters, and ethnic newspapers.
SERIES XII: ADDENDUM: PHOTOGRAPHS (undated) contains mounted photographs of Italian-Americans, many from around the turn of the century.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Location of Copies or Alternate Formats
Digital reproductions of materials in this collection may also be found in the Archives & Special Collections digital repository.
Italian Americans; Ethnic groups; Connecticut (state); University of Connecticut
- Series I: Administrative Records, undated, 1974-1979
  - Correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1976-1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Grant Applications, 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Map of Ethnic groups in contemporary CT, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Personnel, job descriptions and allocations, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Press releases and publicity, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Progress reports, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Project evaluations, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Proposal for a CT Multi-cultural Center, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Proposals for implementation of project, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Reference materials collected by the project, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Reference materials on computer graphics, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - State Advisory Council, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Series II: William D'Antonio Files, undated, 1946-1976
  - The Peoples of CT curriculum-rationale and format, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - The Peoples of CT/Final report, undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Title IX Ethnic Heritage Project Analysis, undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Ethnic Heritage Studies Fiscal year 1974 program description (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Ethnic Heritage Studies proposals, undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - American Sociological Review, 1975 February (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Sociological Inquiry, 1965 September (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Ehrlich, Howard J., "Voluntary Associations and Community Decision-Making", 1965 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Bibliography on Voluntary Associations, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - New Conversations, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Notes on Voluntary Associations, undated (Box 2, Folder 24-25)
  - Resumes and articles of Dashefsky, Newman, Abramson and Allen, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Bartlett, Robert S., "Ethnicity, Professionalism, and Black Paternalism", 1974 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Dashefsky, Arnold, "And the Search Goes On: the Meaning of Religio-Ethnic Identity and Identification", 1972 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - "Anti-poverty Program is found to Aggravate Ethnic Tensions," N.Y. Times, 1972 December (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - McDonald, John S., "I1 Volto Sconosciuto Delle 'Little Italies'", 1969 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Oral history guidelines, undated (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Rank ordering of CT's ethnic groups: 1970 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Articles by Robert Bartlett, undated (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Antunes, George and Charles M. Gaitz, "Ethnicity and Participation: A Study of Mexican Americans, Blacks and Whites", undated (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Greeley, Andrew M., "A Model for Ethnic Political Socialization, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Stout, Harry S., "Ethnicity: The Vital Center of Religion in America", 1975 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Pisani, Lawrence F., "The Italian-American Community", 1957 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Review of Charles Anderson's Cutting Classes, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Sennett, Richard, "Pure as the Driven Slush", 1976 May (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Greenfield, Meg, "Ethnic and Son", 1975 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Levine, Irving M., and Judith Herman, "The Life of White Ethnics", 1972 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Thaden, J.F., "Ethnic Settlements in Rural Michigan", 1946 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Ehrlich, Howard J., "Stereotyping and Negro-Jewish Stereotypes", undated (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Ehrlich, Howard J., "The Study of Prejudice in American Social Science", 1962 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Morsell, John A., "Ethnic Relations of the Future", 1973 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - "Blue Collar Work and Workers", undated (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - National Institute on Group Identity and Pluralism, research proposal, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Anderson, James M., "Developing Criteria for Evaluating Ethnic Studies Materials", 1972 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Perlmutter, Philip, "Ethnic Education: Can it be relevant?", 1974 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Glazer, Nathan, "Ethnicity and the Schools", 1974 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Glazer, Nathan, "Ethnicity and the Schools", 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Charleston County School District, Ethnic Heritage Program, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Bakersfield College, Chicano Studies Program, undated (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Japanese American Citizens League, Ethnic Heritage Project, undated (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Newspaper clippings on ethnic groups, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Roche, John, "Ethnicity and Assimilation Among Suburban Italian Americans", 1974 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Italian Culture, undated (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Consultation on ethnic succession in America, undated (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Articles by Diane Barthel, undated (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - "The American Poles", undated (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Levine, Irving M. and Judith Herman, "Search for Identity in Blue-Collar America", 1972 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Levine, Irving M. and Judith Herman, "The Life of White Ethnics", 1972 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Simoni, Joseph J., "Ethnicity in Appalachia", undated (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Tec, Nechama, "Ethnicity as I remember", 1975 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Szelenyi, Ivan, "Regional Management and Social Class", 1975 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Dashefsky, Arnold, "Theoretical Frameworks in the Study of Ethnic Identity", 1972 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Senior Centers Study Project, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Levine, Irving M. and Judith Herman, "The Ethnic Factor in Blue-Collar Life", 1971 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Ingman, Stan and Ian Lawson, Dave Carboni, Joe Holtzman,"Study of the Needs of the Hartford Elderly", 1973 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Articles by Wilson Record, undated (Box 2, Folder 70-71)
  - Krase, Jerome, "Symbolic History" (of an ethnic neighborhood), 1973 (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Juliani, Richard N., and Mark Hutter, "Research Problems in the Study of Italian and Jewish interactions in Community Settings", 1974 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Mosaic, 1974-1976 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - CIAO, 1973-1976 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - The Cross-Cultural Southwest Ethnic Study Bulletin, 1972-1973, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Chrobot, Leonard F., "Reflections of a Young Polish American on the Search for Identity", 1971 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Chrobot, Leonard F., " Ethnic Awareness and Self-Identity", 1971 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - New America, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 79)
  - Pennsylvania Ethnic Studies Newsletter, 1975 November (Box 3, Folder 80)
  - INCAR Report, 1974 July (Box 3, Folder 81)
  - Spectrum, 1976 April (Box 3, Folder 82)
  - Intercultural Relations and Ethnic Studies Institute, undated (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - Task, 1976 March (Box 3, Folder 84)
  - Items, 1974 December (Box 3, Folder 85)
  - "Congregations and Racial Change", undated (Box 3, Folder 86)
  - Ethnic Affairs, 1973 May (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - "An Inter-Ethnic and Place of Residence Examination of the 'Culture of Poverty'", 1975 (Box 3, Folder 88)
  - "Multi-cultural Education and Ethnic Studies in the US", 1976 (Box 3, Folder 89)
  - Archaeotext, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 90)
  - "The Schools and Group Identity", 1974 (Box 3, Folder 91)
  - Inglehart, Babette F. and Anthony R. Mangione, "The Image of Pluralism in American Literature", 1974 (Box 3, Folder 92)
  - "Who Do We Think We Are?" Harvard Magazine, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - Ethnicity, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - US-Mexico Borderlands Studies, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 95)
  - "Conversations with Cesar Chavez, George Wiley and Ralph Abernathy," Journal, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 96)
- Series III: Frank Stone Files, undated, 1971-1980
  - Writings
    - "The Armenians of North America", undated (Box 4, Folder 97)
    - Minority Education in Global Perspective, 1971 December (Box 4, Folder 98)
    - "Multicultural and Transnational Education", undated (Box 4, Folder 99)
    - "The origins of Ethnic Education in Conn.", 1978 (Box 4, Folder 100)
    - "The Role of Ethnic and Multicultural Museum Education in National Development", 1977 (Box 4, Folder 101)
    - "The Scots and Scotch-Irish in Connecticut", 1977 April (Box 4, Folder 102)
  - Talks, lectures, 1976, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 103)
  - Student papers, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 104-105)
  - Irish Studies papers, undated (Box 4, Folder 106)
  - Papers collected by Stone, 1971, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 107)
  - Personal papers, undated (Box 4, Folder 108)
  - Cutting Edge, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 106)
  - World Education Project, 1973-1976, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 110-112)
- Series IV: Curriculum Guides, undated, 1975-1978
  - "Armenian Studies for Secondary Students," Draft, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 113)
  - The Irish: In their Homeland, In America, In CT, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 114)
  - "The Irish of CT: A Curriculum Guide," Typescript, undated (Box 5, Folder 115)
  - "The Irish of CT: 1st Draft of Unit 2, 1975 April (Box 5, Folder 116)
  - "The Irish of CT: A Curriculum Guide," Draft, undated (Box 5, Folder 117-118)
  - The Italians: In their Homeland, In America, In CT, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 119)
  - The Italians: In their Homeland, In America, In CT, undated (Box 5, Folder 120-121)
  - The Jews: Their Origins, In America, In CT, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 122)
  - "The Jews: Their Origins, In America, In CT," Draft, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 123-126)
  - The Puerto Ricans: On the Island, On the Mainland, In CT, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 127)
  - "Puerto Ricans: On the Island, On the Mainland, In CT," Draft, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 128-132)
  - The Poles: In their Homeland, In America, In CT, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 133)
  - "The Irish: In their Homeland, In America, In CT," Draft, undated (Box 5, Folder 134-139)
  - Scots and Scotch-Irish in CT: A History, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 140)
  - "Scots and Sotch-Irish in CT," Draft, undated (Box 5, Folder 141-142)
- Series V: Research Materials of Bessie Bloom Wessel, 1924-1944
  - Writings
    - "Ethnic Factors in the Population of New London, CT", 1929 (Box 6, Folder 143)
    - "The Ethnic Survey of New London, CT, 1938-44", 1944 (Box 6, Folder 144)
    - "An Ethnic Survey of Woonsocket R.I.", 1931 (Box 6, Folder 145)
    - "The Study of Ethnic Factors in Community Life", 1926 (Box 6, Folder 146)
  - Comments on the researches of B.B. Wessel, 1924-1938 (Box 6, Folder 147)
  - Carpenter, Niles, "The Cultural Adjustment of the Polish Group in the City of Buffalo", 1927 (Box 6, Folder 148)
  - Clippings from the New London Day: Relief and charity Plans, 1933-? (Box 6, Folder 149-151)
  - Local and general, 1933-1934 (Box 6, Folder 152)
  - Minority groups and social legislation, 1934-1935 (Box 6, Folder 153)
  - General, 1939-1940 (Box 6, Folder 154-155)
  - Map of the dominant groups in the total foreign-born population of each town in CT, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 156)
  - Map of the dominant groups in the total foreign-born population of each town in CT, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 157)
  - New London charity and relief plans, 1932-1933 (Box 6, Folder 158)
  - Report of the CT Commission of Child Welfare, 1921 (Box 6, Folder 159-161)
  - "A Study of the Social and Economic Conditions of the Negro Population of New London, CT," by the National Urban League, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 162-163)
- Series VI: Research Materials on Ethnic Groups, undated, 1897-1980
  - Arabs
    - "Living as Moslems in Greater Hartford," N.Y.T., 1979 April 15 (Box 7, Folder 164)
    - "Arabs Settle Near Detroit in Hopes of Better Life", 1979 March 27 (Box 7, Folder 165)
    - Action: Arab-American Newsletter, 1977-1978 (Box 7, Folder 166-167)
    - Aramco World Magazine, 1974-1975 (Box 7, Folder 168)
    - Arabs in general, undated (Box 7, Folder 169)
  - Armenians
    - Newsletter; St. Stephen's Armenian Apostolic Church, Hartford/New Britain, 1978-1979 (Box 7, Folder 170-173)
    - Rustigian, Arsine, "Preserving Ethnic Identity," Hartford, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 174)
    - Rustigian, Stella S., "The Armenians of Greater Hartford", 1976 (Box 7, Folder 175-176)
    - Biography; Baronian, George Armenag, Waterbury, undated (Box 7, Folder 177)
    - "Rose," Oral history summary, undated (Box 7, Folder 178)
    - "Armenian Education", undated (Box 7, Folder 179)
    - Armenians in the U.S.; Armenian Assembly, Armenian Library, Armenian Studies, undated (Box 7, Folder 180)
    - Barsumian, Nazareth, Stowaway to Heaven, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 181)
    - Barsumian, Garig, Armenian-American Poets: A Bilingual Anthology, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 182)
    - Directory of the Armenian Apostolic Church of America, 1972 March (Box 7, Folder 183)
    - Directory of the Armenian Apostolic Church of America, 1971 Fall (Box 7, Folder 184)
    - Kulhanjian, Gary A., An Abstract of the Historical and Sociological Aspects of Armenian Immigration to the U.S., 1890-1930, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 185)
    - Letters and Literature; Armenian periodical, 1978-1980 (Box 7, Folder 186)
    - Mahakian, Charles, History of Armenians in California, 1935 (Box 7, Folder 187)
    - Material on the Armenian Youth Federation, undated (Box 7, Folder 188)
    - Nargil, Jack and John Hanessian, Jr., Armenian Academic Personnel in the U.S., 1973 June (Box 7, Folder 189)
    - The Armenian Assembly Newsletter, 1978-1979 (Box 7, Folder 190)
    - Outreach; Armenian-American newsletter, 1978-1979 (Box 7, Folder 191-192)
    - The Armenian Reporter; Armenian-American newspaper, 1975 august (Box 7, Folder 193)
    - Armenian Weekly, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 194-201)
    - Armenian Weekly, 1977-1980 (Box 8, Folder 202-219)
    - Armenians in the U.S.; newspaper clippings, undated (Box 8, Folder 220)
    - Publications of the Armenian Sisters Academy, 1976-1977 (Box 8, Folder 221)
    - Rustigian, Stella S., "A Blueprint for Cultural Survival: The Armenian-American School", 1976 (Box 8, Folder 222)
    - Samoniantz, Serge, "The Effects of Genocide on Armenians in the US" ASBAREZ, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 223)
    - Yeretzian, Aram S., A History of Armenian Immigration to America with Special Reference to Los Angeles, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 224)
    - Armenia, an Abridged Historic Outline of its Church and People, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 225)
    - "Armenia Today", 1975 (Box 8, Folder 226)
    - Armenia Prelacy of America, A Brief History of Armenia, 1932 (Box 8, Folder 227)
    - The Armenian Question: A Memorandum, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 228)
    - Etmekjiank James, "The Utilitarian Nature of the Western Armenian Renaissance", undated (Box 8, Folder 229)
    - Exhibition Catalog, "Cultural Treasures from the Land of Armenia", 1977 (Box 8, Folder 230)
    - For One Nation, For One Future (Armenians in Lebanon), 1976 (Box 8, Folder 231)
    - Grigorian, Rouben, Armenian Music: Past and Present, undated (Box 8, Folder 232)
    - Kurkjian, Vahan, The Armenian Kingdom of Cilicia, undated (Box 8, Folder 233)
    - Manandian, Hacob, A Brief Survey of the History of Ancient Armenia, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 234)
    - Map of historic Armenia, undated (Box 8, Folder 235)
    - Nersoyan, Hagop, A History of the Armenian Church, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 236)
    - Armenians in general; newspaper clippings, 1975-1979 (Box 8, Folder 237)
    - Pasdermadjian, H., "An Outline of the Economic History of Armenia", 1950 (Box 8, Folder 238)
    - Sarkisian, E. K. and R. G. Sahakian, Vital Issues in Modern Armenian History, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 239)
    - Sarkissian, Karekin, "The Armenian Church in Contemporary Times", 1969 (Box 8, Folder 240)
    - Sarkissian, Karekin, A Brief Introduction to Armenian Christian Literature, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 241)
  - Asians
    - "Asian Americans," Youth, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 242)
    - The Asian Student; Asian-American newspaper, 1976 January (Box 9, Folder 243)
    - Oriental Music: A selected Diskography, 1971 (Box 9, Folder 244)
  - Assyrians
    - Clough, Samira Khurji, "The Assyrians: An Ethnic Minority in the Middle East and the U.S.", 1978 (Box 9, Folder 245)
  - Blacks
    - Blacks in CT; newspaper clippings, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 246)
    - 9th Annual Convention of the CT NAACP, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 247)
    - Racial Integrations in Public Housing Projects in CT, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 248)
    - Rogers, John E., Inner City, (CT) Bicentennial Booklet, 1776-1976, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 249)
    - Training of Negroes in the Skilled Trades (CT), 1954 (Box 9, Folder 250)
    - Berger, Stephen D., The Social consequences of Residential Segregation of the Urban American Negro, 1970 (Box 9, Folder 251)
    - "Black Heritage Trail"; pamphlet, undated (Box 9, Folder 9.252)
    - Deutsch, Martin, "Happenings on the Way Back to the Forum: Social Science, I.Q., and Race Differences Revisited", 1969 (Box 9, Folder 253)
    - Report of the First National Congress of Black Professionals in Higher Education, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 254)